

Dr. Nilesh Ingale

India Nagar, Near badame Ladies hostel, Latur-413512

8291210068 ingaleyash7@gmail.com

ABOUT ME

I am highly motivated researcher, with experience in electronic structures calculations, passionate about doing research on materials for solving energy, environment problems.

I am interested in incorporation of Machine learning with electronic structure calculation for developing novel materials.

SKILLS & PROFICIENCIES

- Electronic structure calculation
- · condensed matter physics
- machine learning in materials Science
- ADMP-Molecular dynamics simulations
- Gaussian 09, Quantum espresso, VESTA, Tableau, Avogadro software's
- R, Python and Fortran languages

CERTIFICATION & VOLUNTEER WORK

- Masters in Data science by Simplilearn, 2021
- State Eligibility Test(SET)passed in 2018

WORK HISTORY

Asst. Professor

Dayanand Science college, Latur

August 2012-March 2013

Junior Research fellow August 2017 to September 2019

Senior Research fellow October 2019- October 2021

Asst. Professor
Department of Physics
The Institute of Science, Mumbai
July 2019- March2020

Asst. Professor

Department of Physics

Dr. Babasaheb Ambedkar Marathwada University sub-campus, Osmanabad.

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

December 2021-present

S.R.T.M. University
Nanded, Maharashtra
Bachelor's Degree Science,(B.Sc.)
Major in Physics, Chemistry, Industrial chem.
2009

Masters degree in Science(M.Sc.), Major in Physics 2012

Masters in Philosophy(M.Phil.) 2015

University of Mumbai Mumbai Doctor of Philosophy(Ph.D) 2022

PHD SUPERVISOR

Prof. Ajay S. Chaudhari

PHD THESIS TITLE

"Gas sensing properties of organometallic complexes using ab initio and density functional theory", University of Mumbai.

AWARDS AND FUNDING

- 2014-2015 Dr. Babasaheb Ambedkar National research fellowship from BARTI Pune, Government of Maharashtra.
- 2017-2019 Rajiv Gandhi National Junior Research fellowships from University Grant commission, New Delhi, Government of India.
- 2019-2021 Rajiv Gandhi National Senior Research fellowships from University Grant commission, New Delhi, Government of India

LIST OF PUBLICATIONS

- 1. Nilesh Ingale, Priyanka Tavhare, Mohammad Solimannejad, Ajay Chaudhari, Titanium-benzene complex as a molecular oxide sensor: a first principles approach, **Journal of Molecular**, **Modeling**, **27**, **242**, **(2021)**
- 2.Nilesh ingale, Ravinder Konda and Ajay Chaudhari, Volatile organic compounds sensing by Li/Ti doped ethylene complex, Adsorption, 26 (1), 103-115, (2020)
- 3.Nilesh Ingale, Ravinder Konda and Ajay Chaudhari, Metal doped ethylene complexes for hazardous gas molecule sensing, **Structural chemistry**, **30** (3), **1057-1066**, (2019)
- 4.Nilesh Ingale, Konda R, Chaudhari A Gas sensing properties of organotitanium complex from first principles calculations and molecular dynamics simulations, Chem. Phys. Lett. 706, 247-254, (2018)
- 5.Nilesh Ingale, Ravinder Konda and Ajay Chaudhari, Organolithium complex as a gas sensing material for oxides from ab initio calculations and molecular dynamics simulations, **International Journal of quantum chemistry**, 118 (15), e25623, (2018)
- 6.Nilesh Ingale and Ajay Chaudhari, Spectroscopic analysis of Sulphur dioxide adsorbed C2H4Ti complex: A First Principles study, Indian J pure and Appl. Phys, 2018 (56) 331-334
- 7. Ravinder Konda, Priyanka Tavhare, **Nilesh Ingale** and Ajay Chaudhari, Tetrahedral silsesquioxane-C2H2Ti complex for hydrogen storage, **AIP Conference Proceedings**, **2018**, **1942**, **140011**